Drew Johnson

 $404-825-2866 \mid DrewJohnsonGT@gmail.com \mid linkedin.com/in/drewjohnsongt \mid github.com/drewjohnsongt \mid drewj.dev$

Accomplished Senior Software Engineer and Team Lead with over 8 years of experience specializing in full-stack development, cloud architecture, and big data solutions. Proven leadership in guiding teams of 5-8 engineers through the full product lifecycle at a high-growth unicorn cybersecurity startup. Experience in building, upgrading, and maintaining systems at the scale of Fortune 100/500 companies. Lifelong learner, always building something.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: TypeScript/JavaScript, Python, Scala, Java, GraphQL, SQL, Terraform, HTML/CSS

Frameworks/Tools: React, Node.js, AWS (DynamoDB, Lambda, EC2, SQS, SNS, S3, etc), Docker, Spark, Databricks

Skills: Cloud Native Development, Full Stack Development, IaC, CI/CD and DevOps, data engineering

EXPERIENCE

Team Lead and Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2021 – Present

JupiterOne

Raleigh, NC (Remote)

- Project Leadership: Led both technical and non-technical aspects of a teams of up to 8 engineers, translating ambiguous requirements into technical system designs and actionable implementation plans.
- Full Stack System Design: Drove SaaS architecture and development to support 1000%+ company growth, using React single-SPA microfrontends and serverless, multi-tenant, and asynchronous, event-driven AWS patterns.
- SaaS Development: Created core cybersecurity applications and features across domains such as insights/data visualization, alerting, integrations, and graph operations, supporting growth to over 100 customers.
- Big Data Engineering: Designed and implemented a high-throughput (25B records/hour) deduplication ETL system using Spark/Scala/Databricks, which consolidates CDC Delta Lake data, securing 1m+ ARR deal.
- AI/LLM: Championed the integration of AI and LLMs into the JupiterOne platform, leading the development of a feature that transforms natural language queries into a cipher-based DSL, increasing user engagement by over 400%.

Senior Software Engineer

May 2020 – Feb 2021

The Home Depot

Atlanta, GA (Remote)

- Full Stack Typescript: Authored suite of new React frontends and Node/Express/TypeORM layered multi-tenant microservice APIs for B2B/B2C tax exemption software, decreasing monthly legacy system requests by 2 million.
- Cloud Architecture and SRE: Directed GCP cloud architecture, CI/CD, and database migrations from legacy on-premise systems to new microservice architecture maintaining 99.99% uptime for 250k+ requests a day.

Senior Software Engineer

Sep 2019 – May 2020

Delta Air Lines

Atlanta, GA

- Cloud Architecture: Guided development architecture of Delta's first AWS cloud project, implementing real-time, high throughput data streaming from on-premise sources for the daily distributed processing of millions of records.
- Data Ingestion and Streaming: Integrated with hundreds of disparate legacy on-premise and cloud applications for real-time customer data ingestion, standardization, and consolidation around centralized IDs (SVOC).
- TDD/BDD: Created Java utilities alongside Gherkin-based libraries to establish best practices for unit, integration, and E2E testing, achieving over 95% code coverage and standardizing processes across API development teams.

Full Stack Software Engineer (Side contract)

Oct 2018 – Sep 2019

Schenck Process

Kansas City, MO

- Full Stack App Design/Development: Architected, developed, and implemented engineering product specification/sizing tool, saving hundreds of monthly engineer hours and preventing company liability issues.
- Maintainable Code: Strategically evolved and maintained a robust codebase over 6+ years, driving the transition from MVP to advanced iterations in response to evolving feature requirements and technology upgrades.

Software Engineer

Oct 2017 - Sep 2019

Overland Park, KS

Meridian Business Services

- **Development Lead**: Led development efforts supporting company's 2-year 500% growth, establishing and maintaining core engineering best practices while delivering effective and efficient code.
- Web Solutions: Architected and developed ERP/CRM customizations for over 50 clients including third-party RESTful integrations/API development, backend workflow automations, and full stack web app development.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA